<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David McClellan</title>
    <link>https://hacdan.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on David McClellan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 13:31:50 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hacdan.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fuzzy SSH</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/fuzzy-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 13:31:50 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/fuzzy-ssh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At work, I often have to SSH into multipe machines, but I hate having to remember the host names I&amp;rsquo;ve set in in my &lt;code&gt;~/.ssh/confg&lt;/code&gt; file. I decided I would wrie a quick script to solve this problem for me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-code&#34;&gt;The Code&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#cdd6f4;background-color:#1e1e2e;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#6c7086;font-style:italic&#34;&gt;#!/bin/sh&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#6c7086;font-style:italic&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;ssh &lt;span style=&#34;color:#cba6f7&#34;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;cat ~/.ssh/config | grep &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e3a1&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Host &amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; | awk &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e3a1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;{print $2}&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; | fzf&lt;span style=&#34;color:#cba6f7&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This of course requires that you have &lt;code&gt;FZF&lt;/code&gt; installed and have a properly configured SSH config, but I find it saves me a lot of time with remembering host names and initiating the SSH connection.&#xA;I have improvements I&amp;rsquo;d like to make, like a few tweaks to have &lt;code&gt;fzf&lt;/code&gt; is displaying the list, but for the most part, this is how this has lived in my &lt;code&gt;~/.local/bin/&lt;/code&gt; folder since I wrote it. Eventually I&amp;rsquo;ll integrate it with tmux to launch either a new window or a new session, I haven&amp;rsquo;t decided, but that&amp;rsquo;s for future me!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultra-wide Spoon</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/ultrawide-spoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 20:53:03 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/ultrawide-spoon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ultra-wide-monitors&#34;&gt;Ultra-wide monitors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the big push for ultra-wide monitors, and the M-Series MacBook Air only supporting one external monitor, I chose to change to an ultra-wide monitor at my desk. I&amp;rsquo;m not gonna lie, I hated it at first. It seemed to be such a waste of space when fullscreening apps, and as we all know, window management on macOS is lackluster at best, unless you&amp;rsquo;re full screening apps, which is something I rarely need to do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automation Station</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/automation-station/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 20:56:31 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/automation-station/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Improved workflow&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Looks cool (obviously should have been #1)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Saved on typing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Share .dotfiles&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Make joke about dot dotfiles&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Share 2 specific functions/aliases/automations&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-who&#34;&gt;The who?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heading writes it&amp;rsquo;s own joke&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Everyone needs to do this. Regardless of skill set&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Front(end) Back(end) Side to Side</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/front-back-side-to-side/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 20:27:53 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/front-back-side-to-side/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hear me out. I know, cheesy title to say the least, but it&amp;rsquo;s what came to mind when I decided I wanted to write about this quandry of mine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;frontend-backend-or-side-to-side&#34;&gt;Front(end) Back(end), or Side to Side?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That quandry is this (if you haven&amp;rsquo;t figured it out from the title by now):  What stack to work with? Honestly? I don&amp;rsquo;t know. I really enjoy backend development where I&amp;rsquo;m working on API&amp;rsquo;s, database integrations, and the like. I really do. I find it to be an interesting set of problems to solve, but I often wonder if I pidgeonholed myself into thinking that I had to be a backend developer because I&amp;rsquo;m not an artist or designer. Of course all the devs I know are back end developers, but does that mean I have to be one? Of course it doesn&amp;rsquo;t, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure it does mean something. I mean, I really like solving logic puzzles as opposed to converting designs into usable code, but at the same time, I sure do like seeing a project through from start to finish.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Imposter Monster</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/impostermonster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 19:06:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/impostermonster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hacdan.org/imposter.webp&#34; alt=&#34;sus imposter&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-the-imposter-monster&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the Imposter Monster?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; what is the imposter monster? Oxford defines imposter syndrome as&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the persistent inability to believe that one&amp;rsquo;s success is deserved or has been legitimately achieved as a result of one&amp;rsquo;s own efforts or skills.&#xA;~&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?sxsrf=ALiCzsYxSRaF070N5o_WMnsujglUfUuK-A:1654730027752&amp;amp;q=impostor&amp;#43;syndrome&amp;#43;define&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjbkoPc_Z74AhWRlIkEHac0DucQ7xYoAHoECAEQMw&amp;amp;biw=1680&amp;amp;bih=914&amp;amp;dpr=2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Oxford Google Search&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this case, I&amp;rsquo;d say the Imposter Monster is that voice in your head that continues to tell you you&amp;rsquo;re not good enough. Reminds you you&amp;rsquo;re not doing the right job. Drags your confidence through the mud and doesn&amp;rsquo;t let you wash it off. This monster has to be biggest jerk on the planet earth. He&amp;rsquo;s born from a lack of confidence, and feeds on self doubt. Which I&amp;rsquo;d dare say is a viscious cycle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Just Do It</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/just_do_it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/just_do_it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;just-do-it&#34;&gt;Just Do It&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, I failed. There’s no other way to put it, I haven’t posted in a few months now, so, that’s a fail. No way around it, so I’ll just lay it out there. I could go on and on about why I haven’t posted, but that doesn’t matter. This was a no excuse, just do it kind of situation, and I didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now before you go thinking this is a woe is me, I failed, feel sorry for me, that’s not the vibe I’m going for. In fact, this is more of the opposite that anything else. Keep reading, I don’t think you’ll be disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joys of (Soy)lent</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/joys_of_soy_lent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/joys_of_soy_lent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;joys-of-soylent&#34;&gt;Joys of (Soy)lent&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week I went through a life change, one most will probably call me a bit nuts for. I decided to go full time with Soylent. Just to be clear, by full time I mean I’m eating it daily, but it’s not all I’m eating during the day. I eat Soylent for breakfast and lunch, but I still sit down and have dinner with my family. I do this for a number of reasons that I won’t go into, but lets just say full time Soylent isn’t an option for me at this time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pixel (C)onclusion (4 of 4)</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/pixel_conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/pixel_conclusion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;worth-it&#34;&gt;Worth It?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was it? Worth the ridiculous amout of cash to drop on a machine that really has less power than a 4 year old laptop? I’m not sure. There may have been a different tablet I could have purchased, along with a different keyboard accessory that would have accomplished the same thing. I could have used the money elsewhere or spent it on other gadgets. What it really boils down to though is I wanted something that would last. This is a quality piece of hardware that I hope to get 3-4 years out of at least, and I believe this was the piece of hardware to do that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Sweet Nougats (3 of 4)</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/sweet_sweet_nougats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/sweet_sweet_nougats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;sweet-sweet-nougats-3-of-4&#34;&gt;Sweet Sweet Nougats (3 of 4)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;stable-as-much-as-my-8-month-old&#34;&gt;Stable? As much as my 8 month old&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, the big question on everyones mind when it comes to the beta preview of Android Nougat is stability. I see it everywhere posted on forums, articles, and blog posts. For the most part, on Developer Preview 5, it is very stable. I’ve had pretty good luck with it so far, with no crashes as of writing. Now that doesn’t mean I wwon’t have crashes, but for now, it’s all good in the hood.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pixels Everywhere! Hardware Review(2 of 4)</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/pixels_everywhere_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/pixels_everywhere_review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;pixels-everywhere-hardware-review2-of-4&#34;&gt;Pixels Everywhere! Hardware Review(2 of 4)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;perfect-well-almost&#34;&gt;Perfect! (Well, almost)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, as stated, everything arrived on time on Tuesday. I unboxed this beast and went to work installing the set of apps that I figured I would need. We’ll get to the software side of things in the next post, for now, let’s talk about hardware.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the actual tablet. The device is solid, screen resolution and aspect ratio is perfect for what I wanted to use it for, which is mainly editing text files and doing research. For that, it’s perfect. The screen is a bit of a fingerprint magnet, but a wipe down once a day seems to eliminate that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christmas in July (1 of 4)</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/christmas_in_july/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/christmas_in_july/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;patience-is-virtual&#34;&gt;Patience Is Virtual&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July 15th. That’s the day my coupon code for a Google Pixel C expired. Counting down the days to when the dream of moving to said tablet would be shattered. Shattered on principal anyway. There was no way I could justify paying full price for the Pixel C. It’s great hardware, sure, but it’s not $500 worth of hardware.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Driving home from work on Tuesday my phone went off. A text message, probably another scammer. I checked the area code and noticed it was local. It was someone inquiring about my computer post on Craigslist. I was shocked to say the least. There hadn’t been any bites on my machine for a few months now and I had honestly given up hope. I answered the few questions that the buyer had and we worked out a price. Sure, it was less than what I was hoping for, but it would be enough. Enough to fulfill the dream of decoupling from distraction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Post...pwned</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/new_post_pwned/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/new_post_pwned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;new-postpwned&#34;&gt;New Post&amp;hellip;pwned&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;soon&#34;&gt;Soon…!&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today’s post will be postponed until Tuesday 7/19/16. I haven’t forgotten about my weekly commitment, I just have a pretty big post series coming up that I want to spend the weekend on. More to come on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MC Madness</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/mc_madness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/mc_madness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;mc-madness&#34;&gt;MC Madness&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;heading-on-down-to-crazy-town&#34;&gt;Heading On Down To Crazy Town&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, this week I’ve been struggling on what I should write about. I honestly took it easy this week, and was having trouble even picking a topic I could write a few words on. I have a couple of projects I wanted to complete this week that I honestly didn’t even start. With the holiday just a few days ago, I’ve been a bit lazy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dot Dot Dot Files</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/dot_dot_dot_files/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/dot_dot_dot_files/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;dot-dot-dot-files&#34;&gt;Dot Dot Dot Files&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2016.07.01&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dot files. A power user’s bread and butter. We have our special tweaks and custom commands built into our files that tweak our systems just a bit from the next guy. Personally mine are still growing, but I wanted to share them with you for my first blog post of this year long journey. While they’re nothing special, I would like to point out that they do not need to be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Blog Post Challenge</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/weekly_blog_post_challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/weekly_blog_post_challenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;weekly-blog-post-challenge&#34;&gt;Weekly Blog Post Challenge&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;getting-started---weekly-blogging&#34;&gt;Getting Started - Weekly Blogging&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challenge&#34;&gt;The Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You probably should know that I almost didn’t write this post. Besides, who &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; wants to spend a few hours of their precious time every week writing a blog post? I mean, really, don’t you have better things to do with your time than write a blog post? I certainly do, but here we are anyway. Because reasons. I’ll get into those later.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Odroid &#43; Minecraft = Possible</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/odroid_plus_minecraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/odroid_plus_minecraft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;odroid--minecraft--possible&#34;&gt;Odroid + Minecraft = Possible&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ARM based CPU’s have always interested me. Long before they had gained the reputation that they have today, I was hacking away on them. Finding out everything that I could do with them. Over the past few years, there has been a huge interest in optimizations for the architexture along with many operating systems being specificially(at least originally) developed for them. While I’m still working my way to replacing all of the hardware in my house with an ARM CPU, I feel at least in the server department, it should be an easy venture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving To The Cloud</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/moving_to_the_cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/moving_to_the_cloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-cloud&#34;&gt;The Cloud&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-story&#34;&gt;My Story&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An adventure. That’s the best way that I can describe this process. My development work, at least in this part of my life, has always been a side project, but I’d taken it somewhat seriously. I found myself, though, wandering off to do other things instead of concentrating on my true passion. &lt;em&gt;Writing software&lt;/em&gt;. I hadn’t really thought about solving the concentration problem because, who cares right? It’s just a hobby, no need to get serious about it. I do have a degree in software engineering, but I’m not using it in my current position, so why bother?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/resume/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/resume/readme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;david-mcclellan&#34;&gt;David McClellan&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results-driven IT professional with 10+ years of experience in automation, infrastructure management, and system optimization. Adept at designing, deploying, and securing enterprise IT environments across cloud and on-premises systems. Passionate about leveraging automation tools like Ansible, Terraform, and PowerShell to enhance efficiency, scalability, and security. Proven track record of leading complex projects, streamlining workflows, and driving cost-effective IT solutions. Strong leadership and mentoring skills, with experience training IT teams and implementing best practices for system administration, security, and network infrastructure. Dedicated to continuous learning and staying ahead of emerging technologies.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
