<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hacdan.org</title>
    <link>https://hacdan.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on hacdan.org</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 21:24:45 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hacdan.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>#100 Days of Code</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/100-days-of-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 21:24:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/100-days-of-code/</guid>
      <description>I have a problem with staying motivated. As with most people I like the idea of starting new projects, but the newness tends to ween after a little while and well&amp;hellip; the project gets boring. While I&amp;rsquo;m not there yet with any of my current projects, I know I will get there sooner rather than later. Because of this, I&amp;rsquo;m deciding to commit to #100daysofcode .
I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll blog about every day that I complete of this challenge, but I do plan on posting updates from time-to-time regarding this challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Front(end) Back(end) Side to Side</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/front-back-side-to-side/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 20:27:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/front-back-side-to-side/</guid>
      <description>Hear me out. I know, cheesy title to say the least, but it&amp;rsquo;s what came to mind when I decided I wanted to write about this quandry of mine.
Front(end) Back(end), or Side to Side? That quandry is this (if you haven&amp;rsquo;t figured it out from the title by now): What stack to work with? Honestly? I don&amp;rsquo;t know. I really enjoy backend development where I&amp;rsquo;m working on API&amp;rsquo;s, database integrations, and the like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imposter Monster</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/impostermonster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 19:06:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/impostermonster/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s the Imposter Monster? So&amp;hellip; what is the imposter monster? Oxford defines imposter syndrome as
the persistent inability to believe that one&amp;rsquo;s success is deserved or has been legitimately achieved as a result of one&amp;rsquo;s own efforts or skills. ~Oxford Google Search&amp;hellip; In this case, I&amp;rsquo;d say the Imposter Monster is that voice in your head that continues to tell you you&amp;rsquo;re not good enough. Reminds you you&amp;rsquo;re not doing the right job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Do It</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/just_do_it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/just_do_it/</guid>
      <description>Just Do It So, I failed. There’s no other way to put it, I haven’t posted in a few months now, so, that’s a fail. No way around it, so I’ll just lay it out there. I could go on and on about why I haven’t posted, but that doesn’t matter. This was a no excuse, just do it kind of situation, and I didn’t.
Now before you go thinking this is a woe is me, I failed, feel sorry for me, that’s not the vibe I’m going for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joys of (Soy)lent</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/joys_of_soy_lent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/joys_of_soy_lent/</guid>
      <description>Joys of (Soy)lent This week I went through a life change, one most will probably call me a bit nuts for. I decided to go full time with Soylent. Just to be clear, by full time I mean I’m eating it daily, but it’s not all I’m eating during the day. I eat Soylent for breakfast and lunch, but I still sit down and have dinner with my family. I do this for a number of reasons that I won’t go into, but lets just say full time Soylent isn’t an option for me at this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pixel (C)onclusion (4 of 4)</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/pixel_conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/pixel_conclusion/</guid>
      <description>Worth It? Was it? Worth the ridiculous amout of cash to drop on a machine that really has less power than a 4 year old laptop? I’m not sure. There may have been a different tablet I could have purchased, along with a different keyboard accessory that would have accomplished the same thing. I could have used the money elsewhere or spent it on other gadgets. What it really boils down to though is I wanted something that would last.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Sweet Nougats (3 of 4)</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/sweet_sweet_nougats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/sweet_sweet_nougats/</guid>
      <description>Sweet Sweet Nougats (3 of 4) Stable? As much as my 8 month old So, the big question on everyones mind when it comes to the beta preview of Android Nougat is stability. I see it everywhere posted on forums, articles, and blog posts. For the most part, on Developer Preview 5, it is very stable. I’ve had pretty good luck with it so far, with no crashes as of writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pixels Everywhere! Hardware Review(2 of 4)</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/pixels_everywhere_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/pixels_everywhere_review/</guid>
      <description>Pixels Everywhere! Hardware Review(2 of 4) Perfect! (Well, almost) So, as stated, everything arrived on time on Tuesday. I unboxed this beast and went to work installing the set of apps that I figured I would need. We’ll get to the software side of things in the next post, for now, let’s talk about hardware.
Let’s start with the actual tablet. The device is solid, screen resolution and aspect ratio is perfect for what I wanted to use it for, which is mainly editing text files and doing research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas in July (1 of 4)</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/christmas_in_july/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/christmas_in_july/</guid>
      <description>Patience Is Virtual July 15th. That’s the day my coupon code for a Google Pixel C expired. Counting down the days to when the dream of moving to said tablet would be shattered. Shattered on principal anyway. There was no way I could justify paying full price for the Pixel C. It’s great hardware, sure, but it’s not $500 worth of hardware.
Driving home from work on Tuesday my phone went off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Post...pwned</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/new_post_pwned/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/new_post_pwned/</guid>
      <description>New Post&amp;hellip;pwned Soon…! Today’s post will be postponed until Tuesday 7/19/16. I haven’t forgotten about my weekly commitment, I just have a pretty big post series coming up that I want to spend the weekend on. More to come on Tuesday.
Stay tuned!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MC Madness</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/mc_madness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/mc_madness/</guid>
      <description>MC Madness Heading On Down To Crazy Town So, this week I’ve been struggling on what I should write about. I honestly took it easy this week, and was having trouble even picking a topic I could write a few words on. I have a couple of projects I wanted to complete this week that I honestly didn’t even start. With the holiday just a few days ago, I’ve been a bit lazy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dot Dot Dot Files</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/dot_dot_dot_files/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/dot_dot_dot_files/</guid>
      <description>Dot Dot Dot Files 2016.07.01
Dot files. A power user’s bread and butter. We have our special tweaks and custom commands built into our files that tweak our systems just a bit from the next guy. Personally mine are still growing, but I wanted to share them with you for my first blog post of this year long journey. While they’re nothing special, I would like to point out that they do not need to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Blog Post Challenge</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/weekly_blog_post_challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/weekly_blog_post_challenge/</guid>
      <description>Weekly Blog Post Challenge Getting Started - Weekly Blogging The Challenge You probably should know that I almost didn’t write this post. Besides, who really wants to spend a few hours of their precious time every week writing a blog post? I mean, really, don’t you have better things to do with your time than write a blog post? I certainly do, but here we are anyway. Because reasons. I’ll get into those later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Odroid &#43; Minecraft = Possible</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/odroid_plus_minecraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/odroid_plus_minecraft/</guid>
      <description>Odroid + Minecraft = Possible Introduction ARM based CPU’s have always interested me. Long before they had gained the reputation that they have today, I was hacking away on them. Finding out everything that I could do with them. Over the past few years, there has been a huge interest in optimizations for the architexture along with many operating systems being specificially(at least originally) developed for them. While I’m still working my way to replacing all of the hardware in my house with an ARM CPU, I feel at least in the server department, it should be an easy venture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving To The Cloud</title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/posts/moving_to_the_cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/posts/moving_to_the_cloud/</guid>
      <description>The Cloud My Story An adventure. That’s the best way that I can describe this process. My development work, at least in this part of my life, has always been a side project, but I’d taken it somewhat seriously. I found myself, though, wandering off to do other things instead of concentrating on my true passion. Writing software. I hadn’t really thought about solving the concentration problem because, who cares right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://hacdan.org/resume/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacdan.org/resume/readme/</guid>
      <description>David McClellan IT Professional, software developer (and I write sometimes&amp;hellip;) based in Bristol, Vermont Email / Website / LinkedIn / GitHub / Twitter 👨‍💻 Technical Experience IT Manager @ Mountain Health Center (September 2019 - Present) A Federally Qualified Health Center - Serving the community across multiple avenues of health.
Maintained multiple Windows and Linux Servers Active Directory Full UniFi Roll Out FortiGate firewall configuration/maintenance HelpDesk Coordinator @ Mount Mansfield Unified Union School District (July 2015 - September 2019) K12 Education School District with a heavy focus on Technology.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
